

8152 Cool Ridge Drive SW, Byron Center, Mi 49315

□ 708-689-7128 | ☑ oneilljohnpaul36@gmail.com | 🏕 oneilljp.github.io | 🖸 oneilljp

## **Summary**

Third Year Computer Science student at the University of Michigan. 2.5 years of programming coursework with a record of success and a desire to learn more. Long history of proven servant leadership skills, with a passion for open source software and improving the accessibility of technology and computer science education to underrepresented communities.

## **Projects**

#### Algovisualizer

JavaScript, HTML Canvas

May 2020 - Aug. 2020

• Created a website that visualizes different pathfinding and maze generation algorithms on a two-dimensional grid in order for individuals to have a visual aide to assist in learning these algorithms.

#### Technical Skills

Languages C++, C, Node.js, Python
Back-end Flask, SQLite, REST API
Front-end React, HTML5, css,

Operating Systems Linux, Windows, Mac

**Version Control** Git

#### Education

**University of Michigan** 

B.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE - GPA: 3.64

Ann Arbor, MI

Anticipated Graduation: May 2022

Relevant Coursework:

- EECS 281: Data Structures and Algorithms
- EECS 370: Computer Organization
- EECS 376: Foundations of Computer Science
- EECS 388; Introduction to Cybersecurity (Currently Enrolled)
- EECS 485: Websystems (Currently Enrolled)

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

1Cademy Ann Arbor, MI

Python Community Co-Leader

January 2021 - Present

- Lead a team of interns in aggregating knowledge about the Python Programming Language on the large-scale platform 1Cademy, with a focus on organizing information in nodes through prerequisite linking.
- Coordinated interns in assessing the specific needs of other communities on the 1Cademy platform, and in implementing programming solutions to alleviate said needs in smaller project teams.

University of Michigan Ann Arbor, MI

RESIDENTIAL ADVISOR

August 2020 - Present

- Built community in the South Quadrangle Residence hall by participating in and encouraging casual social interaction, planning and implementing social programming, and demonstrating consistent availability and accessibility to residents.
- Supported the needs of residents through intentional interactions and virtual activities, connecting residents to campus resources, and responding to crisis situations.

University of Michigan Ann Arbor, MI

COMMUNITY CENTER ASSISTANT

August 2019 - March 2020

- Created an approachable and service-oriented environment at the South Quadrangle Community Center by assisting residents in navigating the first- and second-year housing experience and the transition into a collegiate atmosphere.
- Acted as a liaison between residents and administrative staff to best provide the resources necessary to ensure that needs are met with quality customer service skills and follow-up to ensure resolution.